

Ismael BEN-YELUN

AERONAUTICAL ENGINEER PhD Candidate



+34 658 973 082



i.binsenser@gmail.com



Doctor Esquerdo, 170 28007 Madrid, SPAIN



linkedin.com/in/ismael-benvelun-insenser/



https://scholar.google.com/ citations?user=nKBUYzYAA

EXPERIENCE

Assistant Professor and PhD Student

Sep 2020 - Currently

Research Fellow (France) May 2023 - Oct 2023

Research Fellow (UK)

Sep 2022 - Feb 2023

Stress & ML Engineer intern

Mar 2019 - Mar 2020

Research Collaborator

Sep 2018 - Nov 2019

Simulation Engineer intern

Jul 2018 - Aug 2018

Manufacturing Eng. trainee

Jan 2017 - May 2017

Research Collaborator

Sep 2016 - Jul 2017

Universidad Politécnica de Madrid **Computational Mechanics:**

- Topology Optimization; Mechanical metamaterials
- ML applications for Structural Health Monitoring (SHM) Teaching Assistant. Subjects:
- Solid Mechanics; Strength of Materials and Elasticity Supervision of 6 end-of-degree projects:
- 2 published manuscripts

École Nationale Supérieure d'Arts et Métiers

Data-driven description of lattice materials

University of Cambridge

Robust topology optimization of lattice structures with spatially correlated uncertainties

AIRBUS Spain

Surrogate models development for airframe structural analysis. Full Data Analytics Cycle

Universidad Politécnica de Madrid

Data-driven models for hyperelastic materials

GMV

Inertial Measurement Units (IMUs) simulation

AIRBUS Spain

Lean Manufacturing and layout management

Universidad Politécnica de Madrid

Coursera (Stanford University)

Machine Learning and Neural Networks

Universidad Politécnica de Madrid

Best record in Aircraft Intensification

Universidad Politécnica de Madrid

Electricity cost optimization in an energy plant

EDUCATION

Machine Learning Course

Feb 2019 - Apr 2019

Master of Science in Aeronautical Engineering

Sep 2017 - Sep 2019

Bachelor's Degree in Aerospace Engineering

Sep 2013 - Jul 2017

with Neural Networks: Cum Laude with honors

Excellent academic record (top 5% students)

Master Thesis in Structural Analysis prediction

Final Thesis: Cum Laude

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Award for best teacher in second year of Aerospace Engineering 2021-2022
- AIRBUS Chair Diploma for best record in Aircraft Intensification in Master
- Excellent Academic Achievement (top 20) in Master and Bachelor's Degrees
- Scholarship for Academic Excellence in 2012-13, 2013-14, 2014-15
- University Entrance Test Best 100 marks in Madrid

PROFILE

Aeronautical Engineer passionate about learning. Problem-solving and proactive attitude. Strong technical and programming skills.

Finishing a PhD in computational mechanics, focused on structural optimization and metamaterials with machine learning techniques. Previous experience in Airframe Data Analytics at AIRBUS.

RESEARCH AREAS

Topology Optimization, Graph Neural Networks. Data-driven/Physics-based Machine Learning, Metamaterials

- 7 first-author publications (9 in total)
- Brain cancer software
- Metamaterial patent
- Paper awarded with Editor's choice

IT SKILLS

Python

MATLAB Julia **TensorFlow** Fortran

C++

HyperWorks

ParaView

LINUX MS Office

LANGUAGES

Spanish

English